Finding Aid for the Horace Tapscott Papers PASC-M.0237
UCLA Library Special Collections
Horace Tapscott papers
1960-2002
UCLA Library Special Collections
Tapscott, Horace
PASC-M.0237
37.5 linear feet (77 boxes)
The collection consists of sound recordings, musical compositions and arrangements of Horace Tapscott and other composers, and the performances of the Pan Afrikan Peoples Arkestra and the Union of God's Musicians and Artists Ascension. The collection is in the midst of being processed, and updates will be made to this finding aid periodically.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audiovisual materials. For information about the access status of the material that you are looking for, refer to the Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Cecilia Tapscott, 2003.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9949077323606533
Biography
Horace Elva Tapscott (b. Houston, 6 April 1934; d. Los Angeles, 27 Feb 1999) began piano studies at the age of six with his mother, the pianist Mary Lou Malone, and took up trombone two years later. His family moved to Los Angeles in 1943 and he studied trombone in school, playing with Frank Morgan in a high-school band; other young associates from this period included Don Cherry and Billy Higgins. Tapscott worked with Gerald Wilson's orchestra before graduating from Jefferson High School in 1952. After studying briefly at Los Angeles City College he enlisted in the air force, and served in a band in Wyoming (1953-7). He then returned to Los Angeles and worked with various local bands before touring as a trombonist with Lionel Hampton (1959 to early 1961), for whom he also wrote a number of arrangements and at times sat in on piano. By the early 1960s he was playing piano exclusively, in part because of persistent dental problems resulting from an automobile accident during his high-school years.
By the end of 1961 Tapscott had formed the Pan Afrikan Peoples Arkestra, which at various times included Arthur Blythe, Stanley Crouch, Azar Lawrence, Marcus McLaurine, Roberto Miranda, the brothers Butch and Wilber Morris, David Murray, the saxophonist Michael Session, Sonship Theus, and Jimmy Woods. The purpose of the Arkestra was to preserve, develop, and perform African-American music within the community. Its rapid growth and branching off into related social and artistic activities led to the formation in 1963 of a larger organization, the Underground Musicians Association (UGMA), of which the Pan Afrikan Peoples Arkestra was a component. By the late 1960s the organization's continued evolution led to broader community involvement, symbolized by a change of name to the Union of God's Musicians and Artists Ascension (UGMAA). Although activities had tapered off by the mid-1980s, both the Arkestra and UGMAA continued to play a role in their community in the 1990s.
Between the late 1950s and early 1970s Tapscott recorded with Lou Blackburn (1963) and Onzy Matthews (1963, accompanying Lou Rawls), arranged and conducted the music for two albums for the singer (and, later, Black Panther Party leader) Elaine Brown, and composed and conducted the material for Sonny Criss's album Sonny's Dream (Birth of the New Cool) (1968, Prst. 7576); his first album as a leader was made one year later. From 1978 through the mid-1980s he recorded for Interplay and Nimbus, two labels formed by enthusiasts for Tapscott's music. He recorded with the Arkestra, as an unaccompanied soloist, in a duo with the drummer Everett Brown, with his trio (notably a session in performance at the Lobero Theater in Santa Barbara, California), and as the leader of a sextet. In the 1990s he became increasingly busy with writing and international touring. His commissioned composition Two Shades of Soul was the centerpiece of the 17th annual Asian-American Jazz Festival in San Francisco in 1998. With S. Isoardi, he wrote his autobiography, Songs of the Unsung: the Musical and Social Journey of Horace Tapscott. His date of death appeared in some obituaries as 28 February 1999; he actually died on the 27th, at ten minutes before midnight.
Scope and Content
The Tapscott Archive includes both sound recordings and musical manuscripts documenting the life and work of Horace Tapscott, and the music of the Pan Afrikan Peoples Arkestra (P.A.P.A.) and the Union of God's Musicians and Artists Ascension (UGMAA). The recordings include radio interviews, airchecks, concert tours, rehearsals, club dats, studio recording sessions, and performances at educational and other locations with PAPA, UGMAA and Tapscott's various small jazz groups. The music collection includes original compositions and arrangements by Tapscott, and arrangements for other composers. Note: The Pan Afrikan Peoples Arkestra (P.A.P.A.) is also referred to as "The ARK;" to find these materials use: "Pan Afrikan Peoples Arkestra."
Arrangement
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1. Sound Recordings
Series 2. Music Manuscripts
Series 3. Miscellaneous
Jazz musicians -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Composers -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Tapscott, Horace--Archives
- Sound Recordings, Series 1.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audiovisual materials. For information about the access status of the material that you are looking for, refer to the Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  - Assorted Identified Sound Recordings, Subseries 1.
    - The Ark at ELASC, 1972 May 18 (Box 71)
      Four open-reel audio tapes.
    - The Ark at Jefferson, 1972 August 6 (Box 71)
      Two open-reel audio tapes.
    - The Ark at Jefferson, 1972 August 20 (Box 71)
      One open-reel audio tape.
    - The Ark at UCR, 1972 May 20 (Box 71)
      Six open-reel audio tapes.
    - As Above, So Below (Box 42, Folder 8)
      Scope and Contents note
      Movie Music, Larry Clark
      Personnel: PAPA
    - Black Arthur, Black Musician, 1972 July 9 (Box 71)
      One open-reel audio tape.One open-reel audio tape.
    - Black Experience class UCR, 1972 May 23-25 (Box 71)
    - Black Musical, 1972 October 4 (Box 71)
    - The Call (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Checkin' In, undated; pasc-m_0237_022_016; Tapscott, Horace; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape) (Box 22, Case 16)
      CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are available for access. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
    - Classical Mon (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Damian's first lesson on the drums, 1974 April 21 (Box 77)
    - Departure (Box 70)
      General note
      Michael Sessions, alto sax; Jesse Sharps, soprano sax. On container: opens w/ drums.
    - Duplicate Tape #2 for Arkives, 1972 December
    - Elaine Brown (Box 70)
      Compositions: All The Young And Fine Men -- Child In The World -- No Time
    - For Fats (Box 18, Folder 3)
      Compositions also include: Your Child
    - Full Moon Day Concert at Widney, 1972 May 28 (Box 71)
    - Highlights of U.G.M.A.A. (Box 72)
      Contents: And So / Black Arthur and Horace Tapscott -- Herbert Baker, Black Musician / Mr. and Mrs. J.O. Baker -- Nate Morgan, Black Musician.
    - Horace Tapscott Roughs, 1 of 2 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Horace Tapscott Roughs, 2 of 2 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - KBCA (Box 11, Folder 16)
      Lester Young Interview?
    - Kylo Presents, 1972 December 10 (Box 71)
    - Larry Clark's Movie (Box 24, Folder 5)
      PAPA
      Composition: As Above, So Below
    - The Lester Robinson Story, 1972 July 23 (Box 71)
    - The Life of Lester Robinson, 1972 July 10 (Box 71)
    - Marla Gibbs (Box 24, Folder 6)
      Compositions: Checkin' In
    - Masters for Nimbus Records (Box 18, Folder 6)
      Compositions: Village Dance, L.T.T., Desert Fairy Princess
    - Masters Nimbus Records (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Music for Children, 1976 March 10 (Box 77)
    - Op. 116 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      Compositions: Brahms Op 116 (continued), #7 Intermezzo (continued).
    - The Orchestra and Voices in Concert at Foshay, 1970 October 25 (Box 77)
    - Pan Afrikan Peoples Arkestra (P.A.P.A.), The ARK in Concert at The Gathering, Part I (Box 72)
      Compositions include: Little Niles -- African Village.
      Personnel include: Will Connell, Jr., alto saxophone and flute; Black Arthur, alto and soprano saxophones; Al C., tenor saxophone; Jack, tenor saxophone and flute; Walter G., Mark Lott, trumpet; Lorenzo G., Lester Robertson, trombone; Everett Brown, Jr., drums; E. CoJoe, congas; David Bryant, Richard Herrera, bass; Horace Tapscott, piano and conductor; Voice of UGMAA: Aminfu, Chaga, Cemahi. The Gathering, 4506 S. Western, Los Angeles, CA.
    - Pan Afrikan Peoples Arkestra (P.A.P.A.), The ARK in Concert at The Gathering, Part II (Box 72)
      Compositions include: African Village -- Motherless Child -- Black Anthem -- Effie.
      The Gathering, 4506 S. Western, Los Angeles, CA.
    - PAPA at Jefferson, 1972 July 15 (Box 71)
    - PAPA at the Charlie, 1972 September 4 (Box 71)
    - PAPA at Widney, 1972 January 23 (Box 71)
    - PAPA rehearsal -The Day the Sky Cried, 1972 June 22 (Box 77)
    - PAPA St. Elmo Festival, 1974 May 27 (Box 77)
    - Passing Through (Box 77)
    - Poets and Musicians of UGMAA (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Spiritual Classics Concert, undated (Box 71)
    - Tylon Barea Ensemble, 1972 May 22 (Box 71)
    - Tylon Barea Ensemble, 1972 May 27 (Box 71)
    - U.G.M.A.A. "Arkives" #61 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      Personnel: Bobby Bradford, trumpet; John Carter, Clarinet; Black Arthur, soprano, alto; Joe Brown, tenor, alto; Horace Tapscott, piano; Wilber Morris, bass; Stanley Crouch, drums; Tylon Barea, drums; Jim Quinn, timpani, orchestral tom-toms; Kojo, congas; Roho, congas; Jerry Reed, congas
      Harriet McNair - Bertha; Michael Renner - Father None; Cloyce Flaten - Blanche
    - UGMAA Series, 1972 August 19 (Box 71)
    - Widney Series, 1971 August 29 (Box 77)
    - World Peace (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Marty's on the Hill, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      Personnel: Horace Tapscott, piano; Jimmy Woods, alto saxophone; Arnold Palmer, drums; Al Hines, bass; Lawrence "Tricky" Lofton, trombone; Joe Gordon, trumpet; Juanita Cruz, vocalist.
      Compositions: Green Dolphin Street, Take me back where I belong (Max Roach & Abby Lincoln), Summertime, Moanin'.
    - Island in the Sun, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      Personnel: Eddie Mathias, bass; Walter Wynn, drums and percussion; Bobby Sears, banjo, timbales; Juno Lewis, waterdrums.
      Compositions: Island in the Sun, untitled (with son, brother, mother, father, cousin, uncle, aunt, grandmother, grandfather), Isle of Celia.
    - Mexico Concert, July, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      Lionel Hampton (Radio Program)
    - no location, 1962-63 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Compositions: Islands in the Sun -- untitled (with son, brother, mother, father, cousin, uncle, aunt, Grandmother, grandfather) -- Isle of Celia.
      Personnel includes: Eddie Mathias, b; Walter Wynn, drums & percussion; Bobby Sears, banjo and timbales; Juno Lewsi, waterdrums.
    - Vintage 1964, pasc-m_0237_076_026a; Tapscott, Horace; Blythe, Arthur; Madison, Bill; Bryant, David; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:35:32) (Box 76, Case 26)
      Scope and Contents
      Transcribed from container: "Horace Tapscott-piano, Black Arthur-alto sax, David Bryant-bass, Bill Madison-drums. Speakers-H. Rap Brown, Bobby Seale (and others). At Red's about 1964. Revised 31174" Content Note: Compositions- Why Don't You Listen, The Golden Pearl
    - Vintage 1964, pasc-m_0237_076_026b; Tapscott, Horace; Blythe, Arthur; Madison, Bill; Bryant, David; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:35:32) (Box 76, Case 26)
    - 56th and Avalon - In Rehearsal Garage, 1962 - 1967 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      Compositions: Golden Pearl -- Like Love (Horace Tapscott solo) -- The Boys (1963) -- and other compositions.
      Personnel: Horace Tapscott, piano; Arthur Blythe, alto sax; Lester Robertson, trombone; David Bryant, bass; Bill Madison, drums; Freddie Rodriguez, Rupert Williams, vocal on 5th composition.
    - At Mary Lou's 56th and Avalon - In Rehearsal Garage 1962 - 1967, pasc-m_0237_017_001a; Tapscott, Horace; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:49:17) (Box 17, Case 1)
      Transcribed from container: I. Golden Pearl-1962 & 1963, II. Like Love- Piano Solo- 1963, III. The Boys, Renes's Mother, Celina, Sandy, Babs- 1963 (56th St. and Avalon), IV. Rupert Williams and Horace Tapscott 56th St. Garage- 1963, V. Miss June Gatlin- H. Tapscott-1967, Miss June Gaitlin (1967) And June's suitor singing. Flip Side- Linda and Carmell's Composition Content Note: Personnel- Horace Tapscott- piano; Arthur Blythe- alto sax, Lester Robertson- trombone, David Bryant- bass, Bill Madison- drums, Freddie Rodriguez, Rupert Williams- vocal on 5th composition.
    - At Mary Lou's 56th and Avalon - In Rehearsal Garage 1962 - 1967, pasc-m_0237_017_001b; Tapscott, Horace; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:37:13) (Box 17, Case 1)
      Transcribed from container: I. Golden Pearl-1962 & 1963, II. Like Love- Piano Solo- 1963, III. The Boys, Renes's Mother, Celina, Sandy, Babs- 1963 (56th St. and Avalon), IV. Rubert Williams and Horace Tapscott 56th St. Garage- 1963, V. Miss June Gatlin- H. Tapscott-1967 Family Gathering at Mary Lou's 56th St. and Avalon (1963), Miss June Gaitlin (1967) And June's suitor singing. Flip Side- Linda and Carmell's Composition Content Note: Personnel- Horace Tapscott- piano; Arthur Blythe- alto sax, Lester Robertson- trombone, David Bryant- bass, Bill Madison- drums, Freddie Rodriguez, Rupert Williams- vocal on 5th composition.
    - Mother's Day Concert, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Rehearsal at Rose's (Rose Gales?), 1967 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      UGMA Quartet
      Personnel: Horace Tapscott, Black Arthur, as; David B; Everett Brown Jr., d
      Compositions: Free Dumb (Stanley "Chico" Roberson) Niger's Theme(HT)
    - Elaine Brown, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Personnel: Horace Tapscott; Everett; David B; W.Ruff,french horn; Maurice Spears, bass tb; Ike Williams, tp; Elaine Brown, vocal. Compositions: seize the Time, the meeting, and all stood by, a very Black Man, Poppa's Come Home
    - Untombindie, 1967 (Box 74, Folder 7)
      Personnel: Everett Brown, percussion; Jimmy Hoskins, percussion; David Bryant, bass; Will Connell; Black Arthur; Horace Tapscott, vocal; Sis. Francis, storyteller
    - Doug Westin's Troubadour, November 19, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      (Sunday afternoon). Community Culture Orchestra.
    - Community Cultural Orchestra at Marty's on the Hill, December 8, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      In conjunction with the BSA Sholarship Fund
      Personnel: Horace Tapscott; Black Arthur, as; David B; Everett.
      Compositions: free Dumb, Niger's Theme
    - Quintet, January 9, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      Personnel: Horace Tapscott, piano; Black Arthur, alto sax; David B; Walter S; Everett
      Compositions: Fo' Fats, World Peace
    - East Los Angeles College, January 16, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      Black Student Alliance
      UGMA Quintet
      Personnel: Horace Tapscott, Black Arthur, as, David B, Everett,
      Compositions: Free Dum, Pearl,Niger's Theme, Black Ballet
    - KPFK Music for Children, August 7,1968 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      Converstaion only.
    - The Brother's Tapscott, December 30, 1968; Also contains 02/08/1970 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      Personnel: Vincent, cello; Darion, piano; Niles, drums
      Compositions: The Man From San Francisco, Three From Celia
    - Concert Black Music, December 30, 1968 - February 8, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      Personnel: Horace Tapscott, piano; Black Arthur; David Bryant; Walter Savage; Everett Brown. Compositions: Lino's Pad -- John Carter Jr speaks of Billie "Lady" Holliday.
    - Poets of UGMAA, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      Personnel: Charles; Alice; Cheryl Solder; musicians
      Compositions: Fatisha
    - Will Connell's, December 5, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      227 E.52nd Place
      The Black Quintet
      Friday, 1:30 pm
      Personnel: Horace Tapscott; Black Arthur; David B; Walter Savage; Everett.
      Compositions: Lino's Pad, Sketches of Drunken Mary
    - UCLA, 1969 November 13; pasc-m_0237_008_001; Tapscott, Horace; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:43:59) (Box 8, Case 1)
      Transcribed from container: Herbert Baker-piano, Gary Saracho-vibes, Robert Miranda-bass, Steve Solder-drums, John Estrada-congas. Content Note: Compositions- Prance Dance, Yo Yo, Mode for Gary, Rainy Day, Breeze, The Sphynx
    - For My People, 1969 December 2; pasc-m_0237_076_001; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 audiotape; Duration: 0:10:48) 7 inch (Box 76, Case 1)
      Transcribed from container: "For My People - Instrumental & Voices - #12-2-69 - B.YOU" and "William Marshal - BG Tracks / *Overture (73530) -1:11 / *Ancient River (73531) - 1:17 / 400 Years (73532) - :25 / Transition (73533) - :22 / Strong Man (73534) - :34 / Tell God (73529) - 2:57 / For My People - 1:02 / Tell God 'Singing' - :55 / Tell God 'Humming' - :55 // Instrumental & Voices: Cynthia/Vernetta - Glenda/Landern - Pat K./Linda - Will/Willie L. - Scratch - 12-2-69/Bench - Charles/Oscar"
    - Concert in Black Music Series II at Foshay Junior High School Series #2, The Quintet, 1970 February 8; pasc-m_0237_007_012a; Horace Tapscott Quintet; John Carter & Bobby Bradford Quartet; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:29:59) (Box 7, Case 12)
      Transcribed from container: "#2870 YOU U.G.M.A. Archives" Content Note: Compositions- Sketches of Drunken Mary, Lino's Pad, Sketches of Charlie Parker. Personnel introduced in beginning of recording
    - U.G.M.A Rehearsal, 1969 December 6; pasc-m_0237_007_012b; Tapscott, Horace; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:25:52) (Box 7, Case 12)
    - Will Connell's, December 12, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Friday 4pm
      Personnel: Horace Tapscott; Black; Arthur; David B; Walter Savage; Everett.
      Compositions: Future Sally's Time (Stanley Crouch), World Peace (with or without People) (by Everett Brown, Jr)
      Notes: in audience - Carrie, mother of the twins, Lino, Harold Land
    - [No location], 1970 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      Personnel: Horace Tapscott; Everett Drums; Hines Bass; Preton Flute; Speedy Mike
    - [No location], 1970 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      Tape damaged, inaudible
    - Selections From Several Concerts, 1970; 7" open reel audio tape (Box 76, Folder 30)
      The Society for the Preservation of Black Music
      Compositions: Freedom - L.A. County Museum, 07/20; The Funeral - Foshay J.H., 05/31; In A Sentimental Mood - Malcolm X Center, 06/??; Lino';s Pad - Foshay J.H., 02/08; The Grip - L.A. County Museum, 07/20; The Giant - Jordan High, 06/14; Little A's Chant - H. Baker Memorial, 06/21; Effie - Jordan High, 06/14
    - KPFK Radio Program excerpts, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Compositions: Why Don't you listen (HT), the Funeral (HT), Black Woman, I love you (Nate Morgan), the Vision (HT)
    - Malcolm X Center, January 9, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      ( first recording at)
      Personnel:Horace Tapscott
      Compositions: Lush Life, the Call, Little A's Chant (Herbie Bakler)
    - Mt. San Antonio College, January 15, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      Convocation to Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.( his birthday)
      11 am - 12pm Watts Jazz Quintet
      Personnel: Horace Tapscott; Edwin Pleasnat, reeds; Ike Williams, tp; David B; Everett.
    - Greg's Refresher Course, January 18, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      KUSC - FM, Greg Kufahamu's show. Personnel: Horace Tapscott,piano.
    - Foshay Jr. HS. Series #1 - Sunday Concert in Black Music, 1970 January 25; pasc-m_0237_007_011a; John Carter & Bobby Bradford Quartet; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:31:12) (Box 7, Case 11)
      Transcribed from container: "Year of UGMAA 3-5pm; #12570 YOU; Society for the Preservation of Black Music" Content Note: Personnel- Horace Tapscott, Black Arthur, David B, Walter Savage, Everett. Composition-Encounter, Village Dancers, Short Ballad, In the Vineyard
    - Foshay Jr. HS. Series #1 - Sunday Concert in Black Music, 1970 January 25; pasc-m_0237_007_011b; John Carter & Bobby Bradford Quartet; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:24:42) (Box 7, Case 11)
    - Foshay Jr. H.S. - Sunday Concert in Black Music, 3-5 pm, January 25, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 11)
      The Quintet
      Personnel: Horace Tapscott; Bladck Arthur; David B; Walter Savage; Everett
      Compositions: Sandy and Niles, Nyja's Theme, At the Crossroads
      Carter-Bradford Quartet with Tom and Bruz
      Compositions: Encounter
    - Foshay Junior High School 02/22/1970, 1970 February 22; pasc-m_0237_037_001a; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 audiotape; Duration: 0:32:36) (Box 37, Case 1)
      Tape 1 of 4. Herbie Baker Quintet Personnel: Baker, piano; Gary Saracho, vibes; Roberto Miranda, bass; Gerald Hayes, alto sax, flute; Steve Solder, drums Compositions: Flight 17, Yo Yo, For J.O.B., St. Michael
    - Foshay Junior High School 02/22/1970, 1970 February 22; pasc-m_0237_037_001b; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 audiotape; Duration: 0:33:05) (Box 37, Case 1)
    - Foshay Junior High School 02/22/1970, 1970 February 22; pasc-m_0237_037_002a; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 audiotape; Duration: 0:27:46) (Box 37, Case 2)
      Tape 2 of 4. Herbie Baker Quintet Personnel: Baker, piano; Gary Saracho, vibes; Roberto Miranda, bass; Gerald Hayes, alto sax, flute; Steve Solder, drums Compositions: Flight 17, Yo Yo, For J.O.B., St. Michael
    - Foshay Junior High School 02/22/1970, 1970 February 22; pasc-m_0237_037_002b; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 audiotape; Duration: 0:30:32) (Box 37, Case 2)
    - Foshay Junior High School 02/22/1970, 1970 February 22; pasc-m_0237_037_003a; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 audiotape; Duration: 0:32:12) (Box 37, Case 3)
      Tape 3 of 4. Quintet and Voices Personnel: Horace Tapscott; Black Arthur; David B; Water S; Everett, vocalists (Charles Butler, Cynthia Hunt, Glenda Smith, Will Connell, Ben Guyen, Oscar Corma, Linda Hill, Carol, Fay, Lurma) Compositions: Lonesome Lover, Golden Pearl, Why Don't You Listen; Effi
    - Foshay Junior High School 02/22/1970, 1970 February 22; pasc-m_0237_037_003b; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 audiotape; Duration: 0:32:05) (Box 37, Case 3)
    - Foshay Junior High School 02/22/1970, 1970 February 22; pasc-m_0237_037_004; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 audiotape; Duration: 0:48:13) (Box 37, Case 4)
      Tape 4 of 4. Interview with John Kinsey Personnel: Herbie Baker, piano Compositions: Song of Genesis
    - Horace Tapscott Quintet Concert at Foshay, March 8, 1970 (Box 37, Folder 5)
      Personnel: Black Arthur, alto; David Bryant, bass; Walter Savage, bass; Everett Brown, drums; horace Tapscott, piano, conductor
      Compositions: The Dark Tree, The Grip, Effie
    - Sunday Concert in Black Music at Foshay Series 4, The Quintet, Side 1, 1970 March 8; pasc-m_0237_037_006a; Horace Tapscott Quintet; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:30:50) (Box 37, Case 6)